Morning, captain.
Agent Lisbon.
Jane, consultant.
What do we have here?
Thanks for stepping in.
Homicide Unit owes you one.
Jane.
- You're that psychic fella.
- Right.
Me? I don't
buy into that ESP crap.
- No offense.
- None taken.
Here we have
Ivor Rassmussen, age 34.
Address, River Park.
No sign of the murder weapon.
Store security was
on the scene pretty fast.
We were able
to detain everybody
who was in
the section at the time.
We're holding them over
in the furniture department.
So, Carnac,
what does Ivor say?
- He tell you who done it?
- Huh.
Leather pants, musky cologne,
phallic jewelry.
A ladies' man.
Went after high-end cougars
with moderate success.
Casual cocaine user.
Plays guitar, not well.
Works in the noncreative end
of a creative business.
Advertising, maybe nothing worth
killing anyone over anyway.
So he died
for romantic reasons.
Where are those suspects
you mentioned?
- The witnesses?
- Whatever.
Take it down a notch.
Take it down three notches.
Okay. Under control.
We'll get this done quick
and be on our way.
Hello.
We're from the CBI.
'It may well be that
one of you is the murderer.'
If that's so,
I'm gonna find out who.
These two are innocent.
They can go.
Uh, stick around.
We're gonna need a statement.
Neil.
What's the worst mistake
you've ever made? Quick.
Uh, first marriage.
Good answer.
Why so nervous?
I'm not. I just, I..
You. Your name?
- Candice.
I like that name.
Oh.
Here. Thank you.
- Hey!
- It's okay. I'm a consultant.
'Candice, take my advice.
Forgive your mother.'
- Maybe the headaches will stop.
- I love my mother.
Oh, I'm wrong.
Ignore my advice.
- You. Your name.
- Reed.
Excuse me.
This is a joke, right?
A joke?
A man has been killed here.
Is that funny to you?
- Are you amused?
- No, but--
Then, sit.
Reed, quick question.
Green Lantern versus Thor.
Who wins?
- Thor.
- Oh, yeah.
- Why'd you kill Rassmussen?
- I didn't.
Alright.
Now, you, Miss Grumpy
And Entitled. What's your story?
My name is Mandy Schultz.
And I'll have you know that my--
Let me guess. Your husband
is a very important person.
He is, as it happens.
John's on
the Modesto City Council.
Ah.
And this is
totally unprofessional
and disrespectful.
I'll have my husband take this
up with your superiors.
Mandy, Mandy, Mandy.
The diet pills
are messing with your mind.
This is Sacramento,
the big city.
Your husband means nothing here.
Okay, that's enough.
Agent Lisbon?
- Give him another moment.
- We don't need a moment.
Case is all but closed.
Mandy here is gonna lead us
right to the murder weapon.
- What?
- Take my hands.
I need physical contact
to read your mind.
- You're nuts.
- Prove it.
If I'm wrong, if we
can't find the murder weapon
then I look like an idiot.
Yes, you will.
- What are you--
- Don't speak.
[instrumental music]
Voila!
'The murder weapon.'
This is crazy.
I had no idea that was there.
How could you direct us right to
it if you didn't put it there?
I didn't.
I-I don't know.
But I-I didn't kill that man.
I-I didn't!
She's right. She has nothing
to do with the murder.
What?
I just used her as a decoy
to lull the real killer
into giving me
clean directional cues.
Oh, come on. What are
you talking about now?
Whatever way he didn't want us
to go is the way that we went.
- Therealkiller.
- Yeah.
You wanna guess who it is?
Come on, Jane.
- Neil.
- Hey! Whoa!
Excuse me.
No, I...wasn't.
- I-I don't even know that man.
- Oh, is that right?
I'm guessing that
he was having an affair
with your current wife.
You found out and you
forgave her like a sucker.
He saw you here,
probably smirked
and said something very clever,
made you feel...small.
- Grab him!
- Humiliated you!
Get him! Get him!
Stop! Stop! Uhh!
- Nice work.
- What?
- Case is closed, isn't it?
- 'Hey! Put it down!'
[gunshot]
[woman screams]
[male #1]
'I said drop it now!'
[gunshots]
[theme music]
A dead suspect, quarter million
dollars worth of damages
formal complaints
of misconduct from the SPD
and the Modesto City Council.
Those damages were way padded.
All due respect, Virgil,
I was trying to close the case.
It was my feeling that Red John
should be our priority
given the dozen fresh leads--
Stop. Stop!
That's the nub of the
problem right there, Red John.
Ever since the Tanner incident,
you've been runnin' way too hot.
I fear a terminal screw-up
is coming.
That's not gonna happen.
- I can handle him.
- Canyou?
Maybe since he saved your life,
you're going easy on him.
Maybe you feel compelled
to cut him some slack.
- Mm.
- No, sir.
That is
absolutely not the case.
Hey, Sam, get in here.
- Lisbon.
- Bosco.
Agent Bosco and his unit are
taking over the Red John case.
What? No, no, no.
You have always been
too close to the case
and now both of you
are waytoo close.
- We need to make a change.
- Can we talk about this?
No. You've worked
for Agent Bosco.
'You know that he will do
the job right.'
You need to let my team
finish what they started.
Teresa, no offense
but you guys aren't even close
to catching this guy.
Fresh set of eyes
gotta be a good idea.
What do you know
about the case?
Not much.
He's a serial killer.
Fifteen victims,
including your wife and child.
I can imagine your pain.
Maybe that pain
is clouding your judgment.
Wow.
And me, Sam?
What's clouding myjudgment?
Good question.
You tell me.
What happened?
- We're off Red John.
- What? Forever?
- He can't do that.
- That's not right.
Quiet.
Look, this is my fault
but it's a wake-up call
for all of us.
We've grown slack
and unprofessional.
Look, we need to earn back
the trust that we've lost.
From now on,
we work 100% straight.
No more shortcuts. No more ga..
What are you doing?
You're leaving?
Well, frankly,
if I can't use this job
to seek some kind of
personal revenge
then, uh, there's not
a whole lot hereforme.
I-I..
I don't make anything better.
I can't bring
dead people back to life.
What good do we do?
We drive around California
visiting unhappy people.
We're fighting
evil and injustice.
And how's that going?
Any progress lately?
We put bad guys away
where they can't hurt people.
That's good enough.
I was doing more good
as a psychic.
I was giving people hope,
at least.
False hope, but hope anyway.
You're right. Best you leave.
That way you can go back
to being a full-time fraud
and we can continue
our useless jobs in peace.
Well, that's actually not
what I said.
- Yes, it was.
- We're up. Twenty Palms.
Let's go.
You come, too, Van Pelt.
We'll take two vehicles
in case we need to split up.
[Cho]
I'll see you
when you get there.
Boss, no disrespect,
but I think we need Jane.
We'll manage.
Maybe we don't
close as many cases
but the ones we
doclose will be closed right
by professionals.
[clicking]
Van Pelt,
it's not a jet plane.
Okay, okay, okay.
[siren wails]
S-sorry.
[door opens]
Oh, I'm not gonna
leave you in the lurch.
- I'll do one more case.
- Do up your seat belt.
[indistinct radio chatter]
Van Pelt,
you come with me.
You guys talk
to the first responders.
See what they got.
Hey, the apartment's upstairs.
We have a female Caucasian,
late 30's.
Ran license down already.
It's a fake.
- We're calling her Jane Doe.
- Who found the body?
The building manager noticed
her door was open overnight.
Last one down to the left.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
[cat mews]
[mews]
[Jane]
'Mm-hmm.'
- What's your take?
- Hit with a stun gun.
Then suffocated
with the cushion.
And they were looking
for something obviously.
- Did they find it, Grace?
- 'Um, it's impossible to tell.'
Well, it seems they looked
everywhere possible. Yes?
Yeah.
So we can assume
that they didn't find it
whatever itis.
How so?
Well, let's say
there's a hundred places
to look for a thing.
How likely is it
that you will find it
in the hundredth place you look?
Not very likely, right?
What else you got?
Um...no drug paraphernalia.
No condoms or other items
suggesting prostitution.
So...maybe a personal crime?
- A husband or lover?
- Bravo, Grace.
Wrong, I expect, but very
well reasoned, nonetheless.
Thank you, all.
Appreciate it.
Nothing off the car, but we'll
have the lab boys take a look.
It's still registered
to the previous owner.
Sold it for cash
six months ago.
So basically we know
nothing about her. Nice start.
She's a law-abiding
middle-class housewife
that did something bad
something she feels
terribly guilty about.
Guilty enough
to make her run away and hide.
Hey! That's evidence.
- You know the drill.
- Meh.
If you put "Bullfrogs win
high school basketball trophy"
into a search engine
we will find
Jane Doe's home.
- Can I take a look at that?
- Sure.
[Rigsby]
'It's a working truck.
Dad must be in construction.'
Or something like that.
""Bayshore Courier,"
April 2006.
"County finals,
Lady Bullfrogs dominate
injury-plagued Panthers."
If they list the players,
cross-check the surnames
with other articles from the
same newspaper in the last year
using the word disappearance.
If we leave now, we can be in
Bayshore in a couple of hours.
Uh, we need a little more
than Lady Bullfrogs to go on.
[Van Pelt]
'"Bayshore Courier"
of June this year.'
Headline is
"Police no closer to Dunninger."
"Since her disappearance last
month, Bayshore PD have been
"unable to locate 43-year-old
Monica Dunninger, the secretary
'"accused of stealing
nearly a million dollars'
from her employers,
The Jaffe Printing Group."
- Mm.
- Okay. Bayshore it is then.
So the killer must've been
looking for the million bucks.
[Rigsby]
If she had a million bucks,
why would she live
in a dump like this?
[Jane]
Before we get on the freeway
it'd be good
to take a little drive
around the neighborhood.
It'd be good to find
an empty house for sale.
Why would that be good?
Oh...I'm thinking of
moving here.
No secrets, Jane.
No lies. No tricks.
No surprises. The truth.
Oh? Since when
is that the rule?
Since I said so.
- Or else what?
- You're off the unit.
That's not leverage.
This is my last case, remember?
The only reason I'm still here
is 'cause I'm worried about
how you guys would cope
without me.
Oh, really? So we're
lost without you, are we?
Well, yeah.
Let's be honest here.
- Let's go.
- Hey!
Drive. Go.
Wait. This..
[sighs]
Whoa!
[tires squeal]
- What'd you say to them?
- Uh, nothing, really.
Total overreaction.
'Yeah.'
We need to find
a house for sale.
Okay.
Ah, there's a sign.
Perfect.
Are you gonna tell me
what that's about?
Uh...wouldn't you
rather it be a surprise?
No.
Oh! Oh, look, look.
Strawberries.
- Strawberries?
- Mm.
See?
- How good is that?
- Mm. Good.
Cho, Rigsby, start
canvassing the neighbors.
Van pelt, come with me.
Uh, I..
Lisbon, uh..
I'm sorry for
what I said to you before.
Can I please
continue working with you?
I thought you were quitting.
You know I didn't mean that.
So the job isworthwhile, is it?
It's not that.
I mean, it's not that at all.
It's just..
I have nothing else to do.
No jokes. From now on,
there have to be boundaries.
Agreed.
I need to know that you can do
your work and be effective
without creating a mess
that I have to clean up.
No mess, I swear.
On that basis,
you can remain with the unit.
Thank you.
Here.
[male #2]
'So how did she die?'
It was a homicide,
but she didn't suffer.
We don't have
any suspects yet.
Where was she?
She was living alone in a small
apartment in Twenty Palms.
I thought she'd be living it up
in Mexico or someplace.
- She was always--
- Stop it.
I need to lie down.
Okay, champ, let's roll.
I'm making some tea.
Would you like a cup?
- No, thank you.
- Oh, oh, I-I'd love a cup.
Thanks.
Let me get you a blanket.
I'll be right back.
Ansel, uh, had cancer.
He's totally better now,
but still weak.
It's in remission?
Gone. Hundred percent.
We were blessed.
Even the doctors were amazed.
Thank you.
Tell me about your mother.
Sure. I'll tell you.
Stealing all that money
and running off
that was just
the icing on the cake.
When Ansel got cancer,
her way of coping?
Painkillers
and a sleazebag lover.
That's mom.
Did you know
her lover's name?
Bodhi Andros.
How we found out?
[scoffs]
Ansel goes to meet
his mom at her yogarobics class.
He finds her banging
the teacher in his office.
- Can you imagine?
- Then what happened?
She did her dance.
She's so ashamed,
she's so sorry
she's changed.
Whatever.
And dad was halfway
to forgiving her.
He can't help it.
He loves her.
But you don't...love her?
She...never had time for me.
So...I could always see through
her charm, you know.
- To the selfish cow beneath--
- 'Kessie!'
Don't talk that way.
She loved you.
Look, she's dead.
Show some respect.
She was a beautiful soul,
full of joy and, and big dreams.
And reality
just kinda beat her down.
But here's the thing.
'It was only because the theft'
was in the news that
the doctors at Cedars of Zion
heard about Ansel
and reached out to help us.
'They took him on for free
and they saved his life.'
Saved his life when everybody
said there was no hope.
'So..'
...you know,
God works in mysterious ways.
Well, you know
God doesn't necessarily--
Thank you very much
for your time.
Yeah. Thank you.
Very nice tea.
Oh, uh, I almost forgot.
Do either of you
know a Miles Thorsen?
- Uh, no, I don't think so.
- No.
Sure?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Alright.
Ansel.
Hey, Ansel!
You know Miles Thorsen?
No.
Okay.
Bye.
Thank you.
- Who's Miles Thorsen?
- No one in particular.
This is what
I'm talking about.
Oh. No, me, too. Y-you want
no fuss, no mess, right?
I am casting
a wide, invisible net.
The killer won't even know
he's in it until it's too late.
Miles Thorsen
is an invisible net?
Yes, he is.
We got an address
on Bodhi Andros.
Cho, Rigsby,
go and check him out.
Van Pelt,
get on the money trail.
Somebody's got
that million dollars.
Start with the dad
and the daughter.
See if they've been spending
money they shouldn't have.
- They looked clean to me.
- Oh, did they? Okay, great.
- Just let them be.
- I don't...I'll check 'em out.
Okay, come on. Let's get
back to Sacramento, grumpy.
- What's the hurry?
- I have a meeting. With Bosco.
Oh. Good luck.
[sitar music]
Great class, guys.
Hey, and let's use
that focus we found
throughout the week, okay?
Namaste.
Okay, thank you.
[music stops]
- I'm looking for Bodhi Andros.
- Crap!
Yeah, his office is upstairs,
to the right.
[Cho]
Thank you.
Remember that time
you said you'd been in juvie?
Yep.
You never said
what you got sent there for.
It's gang stuff.
You were in a gang?
What was the name of the gang?
Avon Park Playboys.
[chuckles]
Avon Park Playboys?
I didn't choose the name.
[door shuts]
And, uh, what kind of stuff
did the playboys do?
- Nothin' good.
- Like what?
Nothing you need to know about.
Mm, fair enough. Your call.
See, I don't think
partners should have secrets
but your call.
Like you don't
have any secrets.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- You know what I mean.
Hey, you in there.
Police.
CBI. Very slowly, stand up.
[Andros]
'I'm unarmed, man.
I have no weapon.'
Well, that's great.
So come out slowly,
hands on your head
and we won't hurt you, promise.
'Comin' out now.
Don't shoot.'
Morning, sir.
You Bodhi Andros?
- Yes, I am.
- Turn around.
Hey. Sorry, I'm late.
Bad traffic.
- What are you having?
- What areyouhaving?
Well, I'll have
a bottle of water, thanks.
Uh, dog with kraut,
bottle of water.
Thank you.
- Keep it.
- Oh, thank you.
Well, I'm not gonna lie.
I'm not happy
I'm off the Red John case.
You might be right.
Fresh set of eyes is
maybe what's needed.
Here's the thing, Sam,
if I may.
I know this case.
I can be
a very good resource for you.
If we could just come to
some kind of understanding.
You want me to, uh,
keep you up to date on the case?
Yeah, sure.
Tell you about fresh leads,
etcetera.
Yeah, let's just keep
an open line of communication.
- Mm.
- Good.
Mm...my wife has me on a diet.
Mm-hmm.
This is like
committin' adultery here.
[chuckles]
Let me communicate this to you.
You're a party entertainer.
A clown.
Fresh leads?
I wouldn't tell you
where the bathroom is
if your ass was on fire.
[chuckles]
Do we have
a good understanding now?
I understand you.
It may take you some time
to understand me.
You're filled with equal parts
self-loathing and self-love.
You're addicted to control.
You're terrified
of confinement.
Who's my favorite Beatle? Huh?
Your wife wanted you
to quit the psychic trade.
She begged you to stop
but you were
making too much money.
You were havin'
too much fun.
You can still hear
her pleading with you.
How am I doin'?
You read the interviews
in my case file.
You can read.
Very impressive.
Look, Patrick
I'm sorry to be
so blunt with you.
Really?
You're not a detective.
You're a victim.
[machines whirring]
You never said,
how was your meeting with Bosco?
What? I can't hear you!
I said,
how did it go with Bosco?
I can't.
How did it go with Bosco?
Oh. Uh...good.
It was, uh, it was very good.
We had a frank exchange
of views.
So he's gonna
keep us in the loop?
- No.
- No?
Wouldn't direct me to the
bathroom if my ass was on fire.
[Lisbon chuckles]
- Think that's funny?
- Yeah.
So that's Mrs. Jaffe over there.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
What are you gonna do?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
If you sit down by the riverbank
and wait long enough
you will see the bodies
of your enemies float by.
Shall we?
Agent Lisbon, is it?
I'm Rhonda Jaffe,
company chairwoman.
This is my colleague, Mr. Jane.
Hello.
Thank you so much for
taking the time to talk to us.
Oh, not at all.
And you wanted to meet with my
finance director, Greg Humphrey?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Alright.
Well, let's speak in my office.
Did you know
Monica Dunninger?
Oh, yeah.
I know everyone on staff.
So sad. The whole thing
is just so sad.
The poor woman.
More troubled than conniving,
I'm sure.
And you know,
it's not the money.
It's more the loss of trust.
This is very, very
much a family firm.
And my father
always used to say
Jaffe Printing is about values,
not about machinery.
Do you know Miles Thorsen?
Miles Thorsen? No.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Seriously, stop it.
Relax.
I saved her life.
She resents me.
Oh, really?
[beep]
Jill?
'Jill?'
'Jill, where has
Greg Humphrey gone to?'
'He's supposed to be in here.'
[beep]
'Hello?'
[male #3]
'Hey.'
Humble apologies.
Small crisis
on the inventory desk.
Solved. Uh, Greg Humphrey.
Good to meet you.
Patrick Jane.
We're investigating
the murder of Monica Dunninger.
Yes. Terrible. Horrible.
You were her direct supervisor,
is that right?
I know what you're gonna say
and yes, yes, it was my fault
that she stole from us.
Mea culpa.
I-I should've known.
Greg is like family practically.
We all make mistakes.
We live, we learn, we move on.
Uh, can you explain
to us how she did it?
In layman's terms?
Uh, been there, done that
with the top men
from the FBI Financial Unit.
Do we really need
to go over it again?
- Yes.
- No problem.
Thank you.
What exactly
was her position here?
Assistant office manager.
She kept
the petty cash accounts.
Coffee and doughnut monitor
essentially.
This was her office.
How did she manage
to steal so much money?
When the accounting and
finance systems were integrated
nobody thought to firewall
the petty cash accounts.
Monica acquired user access
to the transactional sites
and created a false vendor.
I didn't think she had
the brains to be honest.
We don't know
exactly how she did it
because she
fried her hard drive
and she took
her accounts book with her.
Are we about to look at
a whole bunch of numbers?
Probably.
Alright.
I'll wait in the car.
Go.
Do you know a man
named Miles Thorsen?
- No.
- You sure? Think about it.
- I'm sure. Who is he?
- Never mind.
[Lisbon]
'Please continue.'
[cell phone rings]
Would you excuse me?
Hmm.
[Van Pelt]
'Boss, I think
I found something.'
The victim's daughter,
Kessie Dunninger
she handles the family money,
pays the bills.
Five months ago,
she stopped paying the rent
by standing order,
switched to cash.
Same thing with
the utility bills. Paid in cash.
Nice work.
Go and talk to her.
If she doesn't have
a good answer, bring her in.
Will do, boss. Yes!
Why did you hide from us, Bodhi?
Fear, man. Fear.
I've been frightened
for my life ever since I heard.
- Why?
- Who killed her?
Either it was her
goober husband finally snapped
'which puts me next in line'
Or it's whoever she
went into business with
and maybe they think
I know too much.
She was in business
with someone?
Just before she disappeared,
she came by to see me
told me she made
a business deal with someone
that would
make everything alright.
A business deal?
Were those the words she used?
Yep.
She was starting
a new day in her life
and wanted to
make amends and apologize
for being
such a pain in the butt.
- Which she was.
- How so?
She was way too deep
into her family
and to her kids
and all that crap.
- Mm-hmm.
- Loved those kids.
Why do I wanna talk
to her about her sick boy?
- Like I can help?
- You're not a doctor.
Exactly. When we
were caught by that kid
she just...went to pieces,
you know?
And I'm like..
...don't get so down
on yourself.
You gotta loveyoueven if
you're a total screw-up, right?
The greatest...love...of all.
Whitney was right, as usual.
Right.
Do you know a man
named Miles Thorsen?
No. Who's he?
I don't know.
Is that enough sugar?
Yes. Thank you.
So, Kessie,
tell me about the money.
About a month after she ran off,
mom called me.
Said she wanted
to help us out
wanted to know
how Ansel was doing.
She loves us so much,
blah, blah, blah.
I told her to go to hell,
and I hung up.
Two days later, I got a letter
with $5,000 in cash inside.
[Van Pelt]
Any message?
"With love, mom."
That was it.
'What was I supposed to do,
give it to the police?'
Actually, yes.
Well, I didn't.
We really needed the money.
Did you ever tell your dad
about the money?
No.
How often
did she send you money?
$5,000 every month.
Did you ever
write back to her?
No.
I like her for this.
- How so?
- She despises mom.
'Mom's got a million
stolen dollars'
'gets in contact secretly.'
- Do the math.
- Maybe.
No? What's your take?
I'd be guessing.
Could be anybody.
Not anybody. You didn't do it.
I didn't do it.
You're distracted.
You're thinking
about Bosco and Red John.
Focus on the job at hand.
You're glad Bosco has
the Red John case, aren't you?
Bosco is a good agent.
He's as good as they come.
It might not be
such a bad thing
that we're off the case
for a while. We got too close.
Is that what
your shrink tells you?
Everybody tells me that.
But your shrink did
tell you that, didn't he?
Okay, may-maybe you're right.
Maybe, maybe that's the truth.
Maybe we did get a little
too close. I'm not so sure.
- But I'll think about it.
- Liar.
I've got a deposition.
See that box over there?
It's got Monica Dunninger's
possessions in it.
Go through it,
see what you can see.
Yes, ma'am.
Uh, who wants to come
with me out to Twenty Palms
to catch the killer?
Did Lisbon okay this?
Of course.
- What is this place?
- Guess.
- It's Miles Thorsen's house.
- Exactly.
- Who's Miles Thorsen?
- Oh, uh..
I have no idea.
[Rigsby]
'Alright, fine.
Don't tell me.'
- Isn't that your number?
- Uh, yeah, that's my number.
That's in case the killer
gets here before us.
That way he'll call us.
What's that over there?
Hey, we have no warrant.
Don't you hear
someone yelling in there?
No.
- I heard something.
- There's no yelling.
- I have perfect hearing.
- I could swear I heard someone.
[sighs]
Okay, so what are we doing here?
Everybody involved is wondering
who Miles Thorsen is, huh?
The killer will be
doubly curious. Triply, even.
Maybe mysterious Miles Thorsen
has what the killer
is looking for,
what he didn't find.
When they look him up, they'll
learn there's a Miles Thorsen
who lives right around the
corner from Monica. Hey, presto.
This is exactly
the kind of stuff
that boss was talking about.
She didn't okay this at all,
did she?
So shoot me.
'"The Fax Machine Revolution'
'The little box
that's changing our world."'
Why would Monica Dunninger
be reading this book?
You, Cho, shouldn't
enable this kind of crap.
We're not doing anything wrong.
What's the problem?
Uh, burglary, trespassing
willful damage to property.
- The door was open.
- Uh, no, it wasn't.
- Aha! Of course.
- What?
Rigsby, you're right.
You shouldn't be here.
Let us take this.
You go find the nearest library.
Why?
Your punishment for being a
wuss is I'm not gonna tell ya.
- Oh, come on.
- No, I'm not gonna tell you.
Fine. Fine. Whatever.
- Call when you're there.
- 'Oh, ho!'
[door opens and closes]
- So what's the gag?
- Oh, there's no gag.
Solve the case.
I thought you already did that.
I thought that's why
we're waiting here.
Nope. This is, uh..
Well..
This is more of
a fishing expedition.
You know, maybe we get a bite.
Maybe we don't.
That's the fun of it.
We just sit back, relax,
dangle our feet in the water.
[instrumental music]
Now, this guy predicted
that by the year 2000
every American household
will have a fax machine.
Can you believe that?
I had a fax machine.
You?
Yeah.
Wow. Nostradamus
of office equipment.
See, this is why
I don't like fishing.
We're not
gonna catch anything.
We have some very tasty bait.
I'm very confident.
Did you consider that the
killer found the money already?
I don't think it was money
they were looking for.
I don't think
Monica ever had it.
Well, what did she have then?
And who has the money?
[male #4]
'Great bones,
original mid century detail.'
Great new copper piping that--
Hello.
Did you have
a fax machine in 2000?
Um...hi?
No cause for alarm, sir.
We're law enforcement officers.
CBI.
"Kimball Cho." Okay.
What are you doing here,
Kimball? Is there a problem?
It's an ongoing investigation,
sir.
We can't give out any details.
Grisly homicide, though.
Why don't we take a look at that
duplex on Royston? Shall we?
That's a good call.
- Damn it.
- Relax.
- He got my name.
- Well, you spoke the truth.
We are an ongoing investigation.
Yeah, but we're supposed
to be working 100% straight.
Thisis not that.
Oh, I'm, I'm sorry.
Wrong address.
Whoa! Whoa! Rhonda!
Come back.
I'm here out
of curiosity, that's all.
Well, of course.
I've got nothing else
to say without my lawyer.
You don't need
to say anything.
I knew it was you
from the start.
Thanks for sharing.
Well, when I say I-I knew it was
her, I-I mean I-I guessed.
I subconsciously thought
it was her
when I saw a photo of her
holding a large check
outside Cedars of Zion.
It was you that
stole the million dollars
from your own company.
Why would I do that?
Well, degenerate gambling
would be my guess.
'But whatever your problem is,
when threatened with exposure'
you made a deal
with poor Monica.
'If she'd take
the blame and disappear'
you'd get Ansel into the best
cancer program in California
and pay her a monthly wage
to stay gone.
That's absurd.
But then Ansel got cured
and there's no way
Monica was gonna stay gone
not much longer.
Then you had to silence her.
That's pure fiction.
You have no proof at all.
Oh. Oh.
We-we have proof. Wait.
Yeah, where is it?
Here it is. Yep.
[clears throat]
This is gonna be good.
[dialing]
Yep, I'm here.
I know, I know.
"The Fax Machine Revolution"
is a library book
and Monica Dunninger swapped it.
Hold on. I'm checking it.
Alright.
Got it. Wait up.
Looks like an accounts book.
There's a DVD in it.
[female #1]
'This is just to say that..'
'...in case
something happens to me'
that I swear on the Bible
'that everything
in the account book'
'is the truth.'
I know that I've pretty much
lost your love and respect
for good.
'But I hope that
this deal that I've made'
would help Ansel get better
and will make up for some
of the hurt that I've caused.
I love you all so much
especially you, Kessie
'even though you think I don't.'
'I'm just so sorry
for this mess that I've made.'
Please forgive me.
'Goodbye.'
The book
spells out the deal.
Monica took the fall
for her boss
'so that Ansel would have
the best possible treatment.'
Nice work.
[Kessie sobbing]
Oh.
Oh, hi. Sam Bosco here,
CBI Major Crimes Program.
Question.
How do I go about changing
my in-house access passcode?
I got strong reason to
believe it's been compromised.
Yeah, great.
Sure. Sure, I can hold.
[Jane]
Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode.
[theme music]